Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Unterstützen Sie den Administrator! Schauen Sie auf kissasia.cam oder kisskh.org vorbei.
[Shadow Detective]
[Schattendetektiv]
[Episode 2]
[Folge 2]
Why did you kill Fan Kunyi?
Warum hast du Fan Kunyi getötet?
I didn't kill anyone.
Ich habe niemanden getötet.
When he died,
Als er starb,
you were the only other person in the room.
Du warst die einzige andere Person im Raum.
There are plenty of witnesses to that— don't even try to deny it.
Dafür gibt es zahlreiche Zeugen – versuchen Sie gar nicht erst, es zu leugnen.
That's not direct evidence, is it?
Das ist kein direkter Beweis, oder?
Then what evidence do you have
Welche Beweise haben Sie denn?
that you didn't do it?
dass du es nicht getan hast?
This time, you won't be lucky enough
Dieses Mal wirst du nicht so viel Glück haben.
to get away again.
Um wieder wegzukommen.
What do you mean by that?
Was meinst du damit?
Dong,
Dong,
you guys go get some rest.
Geht euch ruhig ausruhen.
I'll take over here.
Ich übernehme hier.
I'm not here to interrogate you.
Ich bin nicht hier, um Sie zu verhören.
There must be some misunderstanding.
Da muss ein Missverständnis vorliegen.
I didn't kill anyone.
Ich habe niemanden getötet.
Fan Kunyi also had a heart condition.
Fan Kunyi litt außerdem an einer Herzkrankheit.
His medication bottle was found at the scene.
Seine Medikamentenflasche wurde am Tatort gefunden.
The forensic officer is collecting evidence.
Der Spurensicherungsbeamte sammelt Beweismittel.
As for the real cause of death, let's wait for the autopsy report.
Was die tatsächliche Todesursache angeht, warten wir den Autopsiebericht ab.
Why do I always end up in situations like this?
Warum gerate ich immer wieder in solche Situationen?
Here, have some water.
Hier, nimm etwas Wasser.
Save your fake kindness!
Spar dir deine falsche Freundlichkeit!
When I'm at my most vulnerable and helpless,
Wenn ich am verletzlichsten und hilflosesten bin,
all it takes is a little act of kindness,
Manchmal genügt schon eine kleine Geste der Freundlichkeit.
and you get everything you want from me,
Und du bekommst alles, was du von mir willst.
right?
Rechts?
That's why you wait until she is
Deshalb wartest du, bis sie es ist
at her most vulnerable and desperate, and then take advantage of her.
Sie ist am verletzlichsten und verzweifeltsten, und dann nutzt man sie aus.
By throwing her a little kindness,
Indem man ihr ein wenig Freundlichkeit entgegenbringt,
she'll offer herself up completely.
Sie wird sich vollkommen hingeben.
It seems there's a misunderstanding between us as well.
Offenbar gibt es auch zwischen uns ein Missverständnis.
Oh, really?
Ach wirklich?
What I saw with my own eyes
Was ich mit eigenen Augen sah
and heard with my own ears—
und mit eigenen Ohren gehört –
is that not real enough?
Ist das nicht real genug?
Seeing isn't always believing,
Sehen heißt nicht immer glauben.
as demonstrated by what people thought they saw about you.
wie sich aus dem ergibt, was die Leute über dich zu sehen glaubten.
I don't know what happened between you two,
Ich weiß nicht, was zwischen euch beiden vorgefallen ist.
but if you're keeping things
Aber wenn Sie die Dinge behalten
from me,
von mir,
you're only letting Xiang Man's real killer
Du lässt nur Xiang Mans wahren Mörder zu
walk free.
Freier Spaziergang.
Fan Kunyi was Xiang Man's long-time patron.
Fan Kunyi war der langjährige Förderer von Xiang Man.
How can that be verified?
Wie lässt sich das überprüfen?
He had a badge from the Joy Pavilion.
Er hatte einen Ausweis vom Joy Pavilion.
[Registration]
[Anmeldung]
Take care.
Aufpassen.
Dong,
Dong,
how was she emotionally
Wie ging es ihr emotional?
during the questioning?
während der Befragung?
Quite calm.
Ganz ruhig.
She only became slightly agitated when Lu Yizhen
Sie geriet nur leicht in Aufregung, als Lu Yizhen
was brought up.
wurde erzogen.
Have someone keep an eye on her.
Bitten Sie jemanden, ein Auge auf sie zu haben.
Understood.
Verstanden.
[Chongde University]
[Chongde-Universität]
So, Fan Kunyi's wife is also a professor
Fan Kunyis Frau ist also auch Professorin.
here at the university?
hier an der Universität?
Yes, indeed.
Ja, in der Tat.
She's with our chemistry department—
Sie arbeitet in unserer Chemieabteilung.
a very dedicated professor.
ein sehr engagierter Professor.
What was their relationship like?
Wie war ihre Beziehung?
I never once saw them
Ich habe sie nie gesehen.
have a single argument.
haben ein einziges Argument.
They were always
Sie waren immer
deferential and considerate to each other—
respektvoll und rücksichtsvoll zueinander –
a model couple we all envied a great deal.
Ein Vorzeigepaar, das wir alle sehr beneideten.
But then again,
Aber andererseits,
what goes on behind closed doors
Was geschieht hinter verschlossenen Türen?
in a marriage—who can truly know?
In einer Ehe – wer kann das schon wirklich wissen?
What do you mean by that, President?
Was meinen Sie damit, Herr Präsident?
Well, once on a weekend
Nun ja, einmal am Wochenende
when I returned to campus to pick something up,
als ich zum Campus zurückkehrte, um etwas abzuholen,
I happened to pass by Professor Huang's office
Ich kam zufällig am Büro von Professor Huang vorbei.
and heard what sounded
und hörte, was sich anhörte
like a frantic and heated argument inside.
wie ein heftiger und hitziger Streit im Inneren.
To be fair,
Um ehrlich zu sein,
professionally, both of them
beruflich gesehen, beide
have always been role models
waren schon immer Vorbilder
for every faculty member here.
für jedes Fakultätsmitglied hier.
Professor Huang is also extremely dedicated—
Professor Huang ist außerdem äußerst engagiert.
she practically lives in the lab.
Sie lebt praktisch im Labor.
She's in the lab every day?
Sie ist jeden Tag im Labor?
That's right.
Das ist richtig.
[Shanghai Police Station]
[Polizeistation Shanghai]
I just knew you'd still be here.
Ich wusste einfach, dass du noch hier sein würdest.
I've got new findings.
Ich habe neue Erkenntnisse.
Fan Kunyi's death wasn't due to a simple heart attack—
Fan Kunyis Tod war nicht auf einen einfachen Herzinfarkt zurückzuführen –
there was another cause.
Es gab noch einen anderen Grund.
Correct.
Richtig.
We found a significant amount
Wir haben eine beträchtliche Menge gefunden
of sodium azide in Fan Kunyi's body.
von Natriumazid im Körper von Fan Kunyi.
It is
Es ist
a chemical that has only become available recently,
eine Chemikalie, die erst seit kurzem verfügbar ist
often used as a preservative.
wird häufig als Konservierungsmittel verwendet.
It's colorless and odorless at room temperature,
Es ist bei Raumtemperatur farb- und geruchlos.
yet highly toxic—
dennoch hochgiftig –
just a few grams
nur ein paar Gramm
could kill
könnte tödlich sein
an adult male like Fan Kunyi.
ein erwachsener Mann wie Fan Kunyi.
What's more,
Darüber hinaus
the presentation very closely resembles that of a fatal heart attack.
Das Erscheinungsbild ähnelt sehr dem eines tödlichen Herzinfarkts.
Given Fan Kunyi's pre-existing heart condition,
Angesichts Fan Kunyis bereits bestehender Herzerkrankung,
lacing his medication
seine Medikamente
with sodium azide meant
mit Natriumazid gemeint
that his sudden death
dass sein plötzlicher Tod
after taking it
nach der Einnahme
would appear entirely unsuspicious.
würde völlig unverdächtig wirken.
That's downright sinister.
Das ist geradezu unheimlich.
But
Aber
sodium azide
Natriumazid
is an extremely hazardous chemical—
ist eine extrem gefährliche Chemikalie.
ordinary people
gewöhnliche Menschen
wouldn't have an opportunity to come into contact with it.
hätte keine Gelegenheit gehabt , damit in Kontakt zu kommen.
Dong,
Dong,
time to close the net.
Zeit, das Netz zu schließen.
Inspector,
Inspektor,
have we identified the killer?
Haben wir den Täter identifiziert?
You're a professor in the chemistry department,
Sie sind Professor im Fachbereich Chemie.
correct?
richtig?
Yes.
Ja.
So what?
Na und?
We've found a discrepancy
Wir haben eine Diskrepanz festgestellt.
in the recorded amount of sodium azide
in der aufgezeichneten Menge Natriumazid
in the university lab.
im Universitätslabor.
Do you have any explanation for this?
Haben Sie dafür eine Erklärung?
I have nothing to explain.
Ich habe nichts zu erklären.
I know nothing about it.
Ich weiß nichts darüber.
You know what this is, don't you?
Du weißt, was das ist, nicht wahr?
Joy Pavilion—
Freudenpavillon—
it's not unfamiliar to you, is it?
Es ist Ihnen doch nicht unbekannt, oder?
You're the one who caused scenes at the Joy Pavilion
Du warst es, der im Joy Pavilion für Tumulte gesorgt hat.
multiple times, right?
mehrmals, richtig?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Ich weiß nicht, wovon du redest.
No problem.
Kein Problem.
Let me spell it out for you.
Ich will es Ihnen buchstabieren.
Joy Pavilion
Freudenpavillon
is a "Shuyu"—
ist ein "Shuyu"—
a high-class courtesan house.
ein vornehmes Kurtisanenhaus.
Their services are expensive,
Ihre Dienstleistungen sind teuer.
and a small badge like this
und ein kleines Abzeichen wie dieses
costs a fortune.
kostet ein Vermögen.
Just how much of your family's savings did your husband spend
Wie viel von den Ersparnissen Ihrer Familie hat Ihr Mann ausgegeben?
to get such a badge?
Um ein solches Abzeichen zu erhalten?
Stop it!
Hör auf damit!
All those nights he never came home—
All die Nächte, in denen er nicht nach Hause kam –
you thought he was
Du dachtest, er wäre
diligently preparing lessons at school,
fleißig den Unterricht in der Schule vorbereiten,
but he was out there paying for pleasure.
Aber er war da draußen und bezahlte für sein Vergnügen.
Enough! I said enough!
Genug! Ich habe gesagt, es reicht!
One more thing:
Noch etwas:
the woman he was seeing at the Joy Pavilion
die Frau, die er im Joy Pavilion traf
was his own student—
war sein eigener Schüler.
someone you probably know.
jemand, den du wahrscheinlich kennst.
By day, they were teacher and student, but at night...
Tagsüber waren sie Lehrer und Schüler, aber nachts...
Do you think he ever spared a single thought
Glaubst du, er hat jemals einen einzigen Gedanken verschwendet?
for you while doing all this?
Und was ist mit Ihnen während all dem?
Stop!
Stoppen!
Don't say another word!
Sag kein Wort mehr!
They deserved to die!
Sie hatten den Tod verdient!
Every last one of them!
Jeder einzelne von ihnen!
So you poisoned him?
Du hast ihn also vergiftet?
That's right.
Das ist richtig.
That bastard
Dieser Bastard
spent our entire life savings
Wir haben unsere gesamten Ersparnisse ausgegeben.
on that whore,
über diese Hure,
without a single thought for me!
ohne einen einzigen Gedanken an mich!
I'm so full of regret—
Ich bin voller Reue –
I should have
Ich hätte
tormented him more before letting him die!
quälten ihn noch weiter, bevor sie ihn sterben ließen!
So you killed Xiang Man too?
Du hast also auch Xiang Man getötet?
Xiang Man?
Xiang-Mann?
Why would I kill her?
Warum sollte ich sie töten?
The one who deserved to die is Lu Yizhen!
Derjenige, der den Tod verdient hat, ist Lu Yizhen!
If I'd known
Wenn ich es gewusst hätte
she was involved with that scum,
Sie war mit diesem Abschaum verwickelt.
I would have made sure she suffered the same fate!
Ich hätte dafür gesorgt, dass sie das gleiche Schicksal erleidet!
You've got the wrong person.
Sie haben die falsche Person vor sich.
Fan Kunyi went to Joy Pavilion
Fan Kunyi besuchte den Joy Pavilion
to see Xiang Man.
Xiang Man sehen.
What did you say?
Was hast du gesagt?
So Xiang Man's killer
So Xiang Mans Mörder
is someone else entirely?
Ist es jemand ganz anderes?
Lu Yizhen.
Lu Yizhen.
The real culprit has been caught.
Der wahre Täter wurde gefasst.
You got what you wanted.
Du hast bekommen, was du wolltest.
From now on, let's go our separate ways and leave each other alone.
Von nun an sollten wir getrennte Wege gehen und einander in Ruhe lassen.
To be precise, we've only caught one of the culprits.
Genau genommen haben wir bisher nur einen der Täter gefasst.
What do you mean by that?
Was meinst du damit?
A further autopsy
Eine weitere Autopsie
confirmed that Fan Kunyi and Xiang Man
bestätigte, dass Fan Kunyi und Xiang Man
died of sodium azide poisoning.
starb an einer Natriumazidvergiftung.
Sodium azide
Natriumazid
is a highly toxic chemical—
ist eine hochgiftige Chemikalie.
its poisoning symptoms closely resemble those of a heart attack.
Die Vergiftungssymptome ähneln stark denen eines Herzinfarkts.
Huang Tinghui discovered Fan Kunyi's affairs,
Huang Tinghui entdeckte Fan Kunyis Angelegenheiten,
stole sodium azide
stahl Natriumazid
from the university lab,
aus dem Universitätslabor,
and laced his heart medication with it.
und mischte es in seine Herzmedikamente.
So you're saying...
Du meinst also...
when I met Fan Kunyi,
als ich Fan Kunyi traf,
he had already taken the poisoned pills?
Hatte er die vergifteten Pillen bereits eingenommen?
Correct.
Richtig.
Then what did you mean by
Was meinten Sie dann mit
"only caught one of the culprits"?
„Nur einen der Täter gefasst“?
Are you saying she didn't kill Xiang Man?
Willst du damit sagen, dass sie Xiang Man nicht getötet hat?
We're not sure.
Wir sind uns nicht sicher.
Huang Tinghui hasn't confessed to Xiang Man's murder.
Huang Tinghui hat den Mord an Xiang Man nicht gestanden .
Moreover, according to the lab records,
Darüber hinaus geht aus den Laboraufzeichnungen hervor,
the amount of sodium azide missing
die fehlende Menge an Natriumazid
is consistent with a lethal dose for one adult male.
entspricht einer tödlichen Dosis für einen erwachsenen Mann.
As a professor of the chemistry department,
Als Professor des Fachbereichs Chemie,
she is precise in her measurements—
Sie ist bei ihren Messungen präzise.
which lends
was verleiht
some credence
ein gewisser Glaube
to her claim that she didn't kill Xiang Man.
zu ihrer Behauptung , sie habe Xiang Man nicht getötet.
But since sodium azide is a highly toxic substance,
Da Natriumazid jedoch eine hochgiftige Substanz ist,
access to it should be heavily restricted, right?
Der Zugang dazu sollte stark eingeschränkt sein, richtig?
Ordinary people
Normale Leute
shouldn't be able to get it.
Ich sollte es eigentlich nicht bekommen können.
That's exactly the issue we're facing now.
Das ist genau das Problem, mit dem wir jetzt konfrontiert sind.
Why are you telling me all this?
Warum erzählst du mir das alles?
What's your purpose?
Was ist Ihr Ziel?
I'm sharing these details to show you
Ich teile diese Details mit, um Ihnen zu zeigen
I have no ulterior motives toward you.
Ich hege keinerlei Hintergedanken Ihnen gegenüber.
Lu Yizhen.
Lu Yizhen.
What are you doing here?
Was machst du hier?
What is wrong with you?
Was stimmt nicht mit dir?
I just left you for a little while,
Ich habe dich nur kurz verlassen.
and you've already managed to stir up so much trouble!
Und du hast es schon geschafft, so viel Ärger zu verursachen!
I...
ICH...
How am I supposed to explain this to your parents?
Wie soll ich das deinen Eltern erklären?
It's fine!
Alles gut!
You two know each other?
Kennt ihr euch beide?
No!
NEIN!
What would I want with someone from the police station?
Was sollte ich von jemandem von der Polizeiwache wollen?
Nothing good ever comes from associating with them.
Aus dem Umgang mit ihnen kommt nie etwas Gutes .
Let's go!
Lass uns gehen!
Look,
Sehen,
that cold case from over a decade ago is back in the papers—
Dieser ungelöste Fall von vor über einem Jahrzehnt taucht wieder in den Zeitungen auf.
with so many new details uncovered.
mit so vielen neuen Details, die ans Licht gekommen sind.
[Missing Case Survivor Returns: Lu Girl Seeks Revenge]
[Überlebende des Vermisstenfalls kehrt zurück: Lu Girl sinnt auf Rache]
Hey, who are you?
Hey, wer bist du?
My newspaper!
Meine Zeitung!
Answer me!
Antworte mir!
Give that back!
Gib das zurück!
I hate it
Ich hasse es
when people interrupt my reading!
Wenn mich Leute beim Lesen unterbrechen!
The Survivor of the Missing Case...
Der Überlebende des Vermisstenfalls...
It's about that case.
Es geht um diesen Fall.
Lu Yizhen?
Lu Yizhen?
So that's Lu Yizhen?
Das ist also Lu Yizhen?
Lu Yizhen! Lu Yizhen!
Lu Yizhen! Lu Yizhen!
Did you really live in that hellhole?
Hast du wirklich in diesem Höllenloch gewohnt?
How did you manage to escape?
Wie ist Ihnen die Flucht gelungen?
Lu Yizhen,
Lu Yizhen,
Did you have some kind
Hattest du irgendeine Art
of special relationship with the kidnapper?
eine besondere Beziehung zum Entführer?
This is a university campus!
Dies ist ein Universitätscampus!
Stop this right now!
Stop this right now!
Miss Lu.
Miss Lu.
Miss Lu!
Miss Lu!
The Republican Daily News is selling well these days, right?
The Republican Daily News is selling well these days, right?
Sure it is.
Sure it is.
Thanks to your tip
Thanks to your tip
on that case,
on that case,
our circulation increased several times over.
our circulation increased several times over.
Just like you asked,
Just like you asked,
I placed that piece front and center on the front page.
I placed that piece front and center on the front page.
So,
So,
you'll keep feeding me
you'll keep feeding me
exclusive case details from here on out,
exclusive case details from here on out,
right?
right?
You'll be taken care of.
You'll be taken care of.
[Child Vanishes at Longhua Temple Fair]
[Child Vanishes at Longhua Temple Fair]
[Kidnap Case: The Abandoned Factory]
[Kidnap Case: The Abandoned Factory]
Lu Jialei.
Lu Jialei.
Yizhen?
Yizhen?
Yizhen,
Yizhen,
are you alright?
are you alright?
Is it true?
Is it true?
I am that child, right?
I am that child, right?
You knew,
You knew,
and you never told me. Why?
and you never told me. Why?
Yizhen.
Yizhen.
None of you told me.
None of you told me.
Why?
Why?
Why keep it from me?
Why keep it from me?
How long were you going to keep this from me?
How long were you going to keep this from me?
Calm down.
Calm down.
Just listen to me!
Just listen to me!
I don't want to hear it!
I don't want to hear it!
Si Min,
Si Min,
I'll never trust you again!
I'll never trust you again!
Yizhen!
Yizhen!
She's here!
She's here!
Lu Yizhen!
Lu Yizhen!
Did you kill Xiang Man
Did you kill Xiang Man
because of the trauma from your childhood?
because of the trauma from your childhood?
Why did you return to Shanghai?
Why did you return to Shanghai?
Answer the question!
Answer the question!
Miss Lu,
Fräulein Lu,
say something! Miss Lu!
say something! Miss Lu!
Miss Lu!
Miss Lu!
Miss Lu, just a few words!
Miss Lu, just a few words!
Miss Lu, please say something!
Miss Lu, please say something!
Yizhen!
Yizhen!
Move aside!
Platz da!
Miss Lu!
Miss Lu!
Where is this?
Where is this?
My home.
My home.
And you're the first young lady to ever set foot in it.
And you're the first young lady to ever set foot in it.
Mr. Du, I appreciate you getting me out of that situation,
Mr. Du, I appreciate you getting me out of that situation,
but we're hardly acquainted enough for this.
but we're hardly acquainted enough for this.
So,
So,
please, just take me back to my apartment.
please, just take me back to my apartment.
Your apartment?
Your apartment?
Do you think your apartment would be safe
Do you think your apartment would be safe
if the university is under siege?
if the university is under siege?
Actually, this isn't the second time we've met.
Actually, this isn't the second time we've met.
The one in the plaid is me.
The one in the plaid is me.
The youngest one is Si Min.
The youngest one is Si Min.
And the one in white...
And the one in white...
Guan Jingning.
Guan Jingning.
She's Guan Cen's younger sister.
She's Guan Cen's younger sister.
The one in light colors is Guan Cen,
The one in light colors is Guan Cen,
and the one in darker clothes is me.
and the one in darker clothes is me.
That year, the Longhua Temple Fair was exceptionally grand,
That year, the Longhua Temple Fair was exceptionally grand,
and the five of us had the time of our lives.
and the five of us had the time of our lives.
It was roughly
It was roughly
when Guan Cen and I
when Guan Cen and I
went to watch the dragon dance
went to watch the dragon dance
that you and Jingning got separated from us.
that you and Jingning got separated from us.
I have no memory
I have no memory
of you—of any of you.
of you—of any of you.
Since you were a friend Si Min brought along,
Since you were a friend Si Min brought along,
that was our first meeting.
that was our first meeting.
So
So
it makes sense we don't appear in your memories.
it makes sense we don't appear in your memories.
What else?
What else?
A month after you went missing,
A month after you went missing,
the police found you
the police found you
in an abandoned factory.
in an abandoned factory.
You were disoriented and barely conscious.
You were disoriented and barely conscious.
After you regained awareness,
After you regained awareness,
the police questioned you repeatedly,
the police questioned you repeatedly,
but it was
but it was
as if you had completely
as if you had completely
lost the memory of that period.
lost the memory of that period.
The doctors concluded that your mind
The doctors concluded that your mind
had sealed off those memories
had sealed off those memories
as a way to protect itself.
as a way to protect itself.
These are
These are
all the reports related
all the reports related
to the incident from back then—
to the incident from back then—
I've kept every one I could find.
I've kept every one I could find.
[Two Suspects Detained in Girl Kidnap Case]
[Two Suspects Detained in Girl Kidnap Case]
[The Killer Remains at Large]
[The Killer Remains at Large]
Lu Jialei...
Lu Jialei...
You are Lu Jialei.
Du bist Lu Jialei.
Were you planning to hide this from me forever
Wolltest du das etwa für immer vor mir verheimlichen?
if this hadn't come out?
Was wäre, wenn das nicht herausgekommen wäre?
I can't speak for the others,
Ich kann nicht für die anderen sprechen.
but I've always believed
Aber ich habe immer geglaubt
you have the right to know your own past.
Du hast das Recht, deine eigene Vergangenheit zu kennen.
Yizhen,
Yizhen,
please don't be angry.
Bitte sei nicht wütend.
I used to think
Früher dachte ich
that keeping those memories away
dass diese Erinnerungen ferngehalten werden
would spare you from pain
würde dich vor Schmerzen bewahren
and prevent you from being retraumatized.
und um Sie vor einer Retraumatisierung zu bewahren.
The truth is, your parents and I,
Die Wahrheit ist, dass deine Eltern und ich,
we all want what's best for you.
Wir alle wollen nur das Beste für dich.
If there's anything you want to know now,
Wenn Sie jetzt etwas wissen möchten,
I'll tell you everything I remember.
Ich werde dir alles erzählen, woran ich mich erinnere.
Even though I firmly believe
Auch wenn ich fest davon überzeugt bin
you have the right to know your past,
Sie haben das Recht, Ihre Vergangenheit zu kennen.
I still hope
Ich hoffe immer noch
you won't let it consume you.
Du wirst dich davon nicht vereinnahmen lassen.
Perhaps leaving the past behind
Vielleicht die Vergangenheit hinter sich lassen
is life's way of protecting you, don't you think?
Ist das nicht die Art des Lebens, dich zu beschützen ?
What matters is cherishing the present and living in the now—
Wichtig ist es, die Gegenwart zu schätzen und im Jetzt zu leben.
don't you think?
Findest du nicht auch?
I'll get the door.
Ich öffne die Tür.
You are...
Du bist...
Mrs. Xiang?
Frau Xiang?
Mrs. Xiang.
Frau Xiang.
My child,
Mein Kind,
you've been through so much.
Du hast schon so viel durchgemacht.
I found this among Man's things after she passed.
Ich fand dies unter den Sachen von Man, nachdem sie verstorben war.
I read it
Ich habe es gelesen.
and felt you should be the one to have it.
und fand, dass du es bekommen solltest.
She was my closest friend
Sie war meine engste Freundin
when I felt most alone.
als ich mich am einsamsten fühlte.
Whenever people looked down on me,
Immer wenn die Leute auf mich herabsahen,
she'd always stand up for me,
Sie hat mich immer verteidigt.
and comfort me.
und tröste mich.
Through my hardest times,
In meinen schwersten Zeiten,
she was there by my side.
Sie war an meiner Seite.
[How do we reclaim the happiness we once knew?]
Wie können wir das Glück zurückgewinnen, das wir einst kannten?
[The friends who were everything, now fading into strangers.]
[Die Freunde, die einst alles bedeuteten, verblassen nun zu Fremden.]
But when she needed me the most...
Aber gerade als sie mich am meisten brauchte...
I thought she had betrayed our friendship,
Ich dachte, sie hätte unsere Freundschaft verraten.
so I shut her out.
Also habe ich sie ausgeschlossen.
[I don't deserve it.]
[Ich verdiene es nicht.]
Stop!
Stoppen!
[Lu Jialei, 6 years old, female]
[Lu Jialei, 6 Jahre alt, weiblich]
[I don't regret a thing.]
Ich bereue nichts.
[Xiang Man's Hospital Medical Records]
[Krankenakten von Xiang Man]
The injury occurred
Die Verletzung ereignete sich
one week before the incident.
eine Woche vor dem Vorfall.
Hello.
Hallo.
Hello, Miss. You're here again.
Hallo, Miss. Sie sind wieder da.
Are you looking for Mr. Zhang again?
Suchen Sie erneut Herrn Zhang?
Yes, could you please ask him to come here?
Ja, könnten Sie ihn bitte bitten, hierher zu kommen?
He's not in today.
Er ist heute nicht da.
He didn't come to work?
Er ist nicht zur Arbeit erschienen?
How many days has he been absent?
Wie viele Tage ist er abwesend gewesen?
Just a couple of days.
Nur ein paar Tage.
You know his girlfriend passed away—
Du weißt, dass seine Freundin verstorben ist.
he's just taking some time for himself.
Er nimmt sich einfach etwas Zeit für sich.
Do you know where he lives?
Weißt du, wo er wohnt?
Yes, I do.
Ja, das tue ich.
Are you planning to visit him?
Planen Sie, ihn zu besuchen?
I'm worried something might have happened to him too.
Ich mache mir Sorgen, dass ihm auch etwas zugestoßen sein könnte.
That's a fair point.
Das ist ein berechtigter Einwand.
Honestly, Mr. Zhang's always
Ehrlich gesagt, Herr Zhang ist immer
been good to us.
war gut zu uns.
I ought to find time to check on him as well.
Ich sollte mir auch die Zeit nehmen, nach ihm zu sehen.
[Shanghai Institute of Forensic Medicine]
[Shanghai Institut für Rechtsmedizin]
Ding Eryi?
Ding Eryi?
The inspector's here.
Der Inspektor ist da.
Thank you for your hard work, Director Wang.
Vielen Dank für Ihre harte Arbeit, Direktor Wang.
Hello, Inspector Guan.
Hallo, Inspektor Guan.
This is for you.
Das ist für dich.
You only order me around like this
Nur solche Befehle kommandierst du mir.
because you know I'm too nice to say no.
Weil du weißt, dass ich zu nett bin, um Nein zu sagen.
By the way,
Übrigens,
that suspect from your recent case—
der Verdächtige aus Ihrem jüngsten Fall –
wasn't she the victim from that Kidnap Case years ago?
War sie nicht das Opfer in jenem Entführungsfall vor Jahren?
Her name is
Ihr Name ist
Lu... Lu...
Lu... Lu...
Lu Yizhen?
Lu Yizhen?
Yes,
Ja,
that's the one!
Das ist er!
My master personally
Mein Meister persönlich
performed the autopsies for that fire years ago.
Die Autopsien zu diesem Brand wurden vor Jahren durchgeführt.
The horror of that scene
Der Horror dieser Szene
is still vivid in my mind.
ist mir noch immer lebhaft in Erinnerung.
Exactly.
Genau.
So why has she returned to Shanghai now?
Warum ist sie also jetzt nach Shanghai zurückgekehrt?
And how did she end up as a suspect?
Und wie kam es, dass sie zur Verdächtigen wurde?
How is she now?
Wie geht es ihr jetzt?
What do you mean?
Wie meinst du das?
I mean, what's she like as a person?
Ich meine, wie ist sie als Person?
And how deeply has that incident affected her?
Und wie sehr hat sie dieser Vorfall beeinflusst?
She's just a suspect to us at the police station.
Für uns auf der Polizeiwache ist sie nur eine Verdächtige.
I wouldn't know much about her personally.
Ich wüsste persönlich nicht viel über sie.
Enough digressions—
Genug der Abschweifungen –
you haven't even mentioned
Du hast es nicht einmal erwähnt
the new findings in the report to Inspector Guan yet.
Die neuen Erkenntnisse im Bericht an Inspektor Guan noch nicht.
Right, take a look at this.
Okay, schaut euch das mal an.
Please take a seat, Master. Let me get you some tea.
Bitte nehmen Sie Platz, Meister. Ich hole Ihnen etwas Tee.
Sulfur?
Schwefel?
Correct.
Richtig.
I re-examined it
Ich habe es erneut geprüft.
as you requested.
wie gewünscht.
While both are sodium azide,
Obwohl es sich bei beiden um Natriumazid handelt,
this sample contains sulfur,
Diese Probe enthält Schwefel.
whereas the earlier one was of much higher purity—
wohingegen die frühere von wesentlich höherer Reinheit war –
the difference is quite significant.
Der Unterschied ist beträchtlich.
Under what circumstances
Unter welchen Umständen
would sulfur be present in sodium azide?
Wäre Schwefel in Natriumazid enthalten?
It's hard to say definitively.
Das lässt sich nicht eindeutig sagen.
Sodium azide is mostly used as a preservative,
Natriumazid wird hauptsächlich als Konservierungsmittel verwendet.
but only for industrial purposes.
aber nur für industrielle Zwecke.
Hey!
Hey!
He's actually walking off like that?
Geht der da wirklich einfach so weg?
Zhang Zhi—
Zhang Zhi—
Zhang Zhiqiang!
Zhang Zhiqiang!
Something's wrong!
Irgendwas stimmt nicht!
Get up!
Aufstehen!
Why are you following me?
Warum folgst du mir?
Let go!
Loslassen!
Release her!
Lasst sie frei!
Let her go! Don't move!
Lass sie gehen! Beweg dich nicht!
Stay back!
Zurückhalten!
Release her!
Lasst sie frei!
Letting her go is your only way out!
Sie loszulassen ist dein einziger Ausweg!
There's no way out for me!
Für mich gibt es keinen Ausweg!
Let me go!
Lass mich los!
Just let me go!
Lasst mich einfach gehen!
Don't move!
Nicht bewegen!
Zhang Zhiqiang,
Zhang Zhiqiang,
listen to me.
hört mir zu.
Shut up!
Den Mund halten!
I-I came here to give you something.
Ich bin hierher gekommen, um dir etwas zu geben.
What is it?
Was ist das?
Something Xiang Man left for you.
Etwas, das Xiang Man für dich hinterlassen hat.
Where is it?
Wo ist es?
On the ground,
Am Boden,
in the bag.
im Sack.
It's a drawing she made for you—
Das ist eine Zeichnung, die sie für dich angefertigt hat.
of your future together.
eurer gemeinsamen Zukunft.
She wanted to return to Suzhou with you.
Sie wollte mit dir nach Suzhou zurückkehren.
After graduation,
Nach dem Studienabschluss
she'd become a teacher,
Sie wäre Lehrerin geworden.
and you'd open a dye workshop.
und du würdest eine Färberei eröffnen.
You'd have two children,
Du hättest zwei Kinder.
and a large house
und ein großes Haus
by the river.
am Fluss.
You'd also...
Du würdest auch...
Stop! Don't say another word!
Halt! Sag kein Wort mehr!